CARLOS CUELLAR

(661) 717-8201 hola@carloscuellar.net www.carloscuellar.net

4024 SE Mall St. Portland, OR 97202

Profile

I am an *Interaction Designer* with an industrial design background and some love for front-end web development. I have been creating experiences that simplify users' lives for more than nine years.

I am comfortable working in Agile development environments, managing multiple tasks and setting goals for a project. I benefit from discovering new approaches and constantly learning from my colleagues.

Experience

UI Designer, Lightspeed Systems; Portland, OR - 2012-2015

Design of cross-platform solutions for My Big Campus, a K-12 learning management system, including Android, iOS, Windows 8 and Web apps.

Implementation of semantic markup and concise and scalable CSS for different products.

Creation of a live style guide used across several web products and followed by the rest of the developers in the company.

Architected Classroom Orchestrator, a product used by teachers in order to monitor students' computers in real time.

UI Designer, HP Agrisystems; San Luis Obispo, CA — 2011-2012

Creation of visual identity, design of interfaces and front-end development for horsepower.com, an ag-oriented e-commerce website.

Web Designer, Micrographic; Valencia, Spain — 2008-2011

Design and implementation of corporate websites for hospitals, wineries and other midsize companies.

Web Designer, Katana Red; Valencia, Spain — 2006-2008

Design of interfaces and front-end development at a digital agency, with special attention to in-house projects (online communities and e-commerce sites).

Academic Education

Universitat Jaume I; Castelló, Spain — Degree in Technical Engineering in Industrial Design (Not Completed)

Universitat Oberta de Catalunya; Barcelona, Spain — Degree in Multimedia (In Progress)

Non-academic Education

Interaction Design Training, Cooper U; Portland, Oregon

Interaction Design: Beyond the Wireframe, Future Insights Live; Las Vegas, Nevada

Accessibility and usability Workshop, Fundación OVSI; Valencia, Spain

SEO Workshop, Infonomia; Barcelona, Spain

Product Design Workshop, Modoloco; Milan, Italy

Skills

Web development skills. HTML, CSS/Sass, Javascript/jQuery, Git, CMS integration (Wordpress, Textpattern)...

Prototyping and design software. Sketch, Omnigraffle, Fireworks, Photoshop, Illustrator, InVision...